WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Tom writes that they've
opened the new sale room.
What about Rose? What does
she have to say for herself?
Oh, everything's good. New York is heaven.
They're taking a house in
the Hamptons for the summer.
- Ah! I think she could be pregnant.
- Golly! Why do you say that?
She says, 'I might be back in August,
but it's a bit early to say.'
As usual, you add two and
two and make 53. Busy day?
Granny's asked me to look in later.
It'll be about the hospital
business. Have you told Mama?
- To be honest, Granny said not to.
- You're mad if you don't.
She's a trustee, she belongs there.
Not all the trustees
can be at every meeting
and I want to see if there
is some way to sort it out
before there's blood on the carpet.
- What is it?
- There's a man downstairs, My Lady.
- Mr Finch is here to see the agent.
- I'll see him.
I suggested that but he said
he doesn't want to bother you,
or His Lordship, 'just the agent'.
Wait ten minutes and show
him into the library.
- Very good, My Lady.
- You'll have to manage him.
I've got some errands to run and
I promised I'd meet Granny at 11.
I want to be left to
manage him. It's my job.
How are preparations for
the wedding coming along?
Slowly but surely, My Lord.
We've settled a date with Mr Travis
and now we have to decide
where to hold the reception,
- what there is of one. - Well,
here of course. - Absolutely.
We can decorate the servants' hall
and make it look really special.
That's kind, My Lord. As I say,
we haven't yet made the decision.
Don't forget poor Mr Finch.
Honestly, Papa, 'We'll
decorate the servants' hall'!
- Surely we can do better than that.
- What do you mean?
I don't want to discuss
it now. I'm in a rush.
We'll have a proper conversation later.
I know it's cheating, but I think
I might get a jar of horseradish.
It really isn't bad now.
- That's not like you.
- True.
We could use it in sandwiches without
having to go through the palaver.
- Can I borrow some soda,
Mrs Patmore? - Borrow?
So you'll give it back (?)
Any more news on Mr Mason?
Only that he's losing home and
livelihood and it's all my fault.
- I'm sure that's not true.
- Yes, it is, I caused it.
If it weren't for my big mouth,
he might've had a reprieve.
- That's not what Miss Baxter says.
- She wasn't there.
Have you finished your order list?
I'll send them out this afternoon.
I'll take them up to Mr Bakewell.
I'm going into the village later.
That's kind. I think I'll walk
down to the Home Farm myself.
I'll join you.
We'll be back by 12.
Right you are.
I'm sorry I'm a letdown, Mr Finch.
Not a letdown, milady,
I wouldn't say that,
only I need to discuss the
estate's entries this year
in the fat stock show at Malton.
You won't want to be bothered with it.
I thought all the shows
took place before Christmas?
They do, usually. This is an experiment.
And you've come to discuss
it with Mr Branson.
I know that's not possible, milady,
but if you could tell
me who's replaced him...
Hold onto your hat, Mr
Finch, but I'm afraid I have.
Mm-hm... Hm.
I see.
I've been working with
Mr Branson for some years
and now I intend to manage
myself, with His Lordship.
- Well... it's a changing world.
- It certainly is.
We're anxious the show
shouldn't be a letdown, milady,
so we're really hoping for a
decent entry from the Abbey.
We did well with the pigs in
the other fat stock shows,
so let me discuss it with our pig man.
You see, these shows don't
have the buzz of a county show,
but a decent turnout from the surviving
estates means they're taken seriously.
The key word being surviving.
Hm.
'Decorate the servants' hall'?
I'm not sure how enticing that sounds.
- It was meant kindly.
- I daresay.
What would you like us to do?
If I'm honest, I'd like
to get away for the day.
Find somewhere local, where
we can throw our own party,
instead of a gathering by
courtesy of the Crawley family.
You do mean to invite them?
Of course I do.
Why, did you think you
would have to get married
without Lady Mary to witness it?
She's an important figure
in my life, Mrs Hughes.
- I won't apologise.
- Nor do you have to.
I just don't want to be a
servant on my wedding day.
Is that so wrong?
What should I tell His Lordship?
Tell him thank you, but no.
This seems very formal.
The Royal Yorkshire has written to
all our financial donors to canvas
their support for the takeover.
- Which you'll agree is very sneaky.
- I think it's sensible.
The principle benefit
of the new arrangement
will be to make our money raising
activities more coherent and logical.
There's no government funding
available, either to them or to us.
Which means we'll become a ward
of the larger establishment,
while the local community
forfeit any claims
to being treated in their own village.
Well, that depends how we
divide the new departments.
In the end, surely, it comes down
to how many lives will be saved.
- Precisely. - Lord Grantham, are
you saying we don't save lives?
- No, of course not. - If you can't say
anything helpful, Robert, please be silent.
- Helpful to whom? And why isn't Cora here?
- It doesn't concern her.
I am the president, you are the almoner,
Dr Clarkson runs the hospital
and Robert is the patron
and his father gave the land
on which the hospital is built.
- The four of us constitute a quorum.
- I disagree.
Tell her about this
meeting and, when you do,
say that Cousin Violet would have
kept the rest of us away if she could.
Don't give me ideas.
I suppose you've settled into
the routine by this time.
I think so. I like it here.
- It's quite a change from Bayswater.
- It's a change that suits me.
I've been getting to know the
estate when I've got time off.
- I thought I'd look at the woods.
- I'll come with you, if you like.
No, you're all right. I like to
walk on my own, if I'm honest.
I agree with you, Andy,
it's very liberating.
If you say so.
Mr Carson, I don't suppose there's any
more news on when you'll be serving notice?
Nobody's going to be flung into
the road, I can assure you.
No, but I mean... should I
start looking for another job?
How could it hurt?
At least you know you won't be asked to
leave until you've got somewhere to go.
- I don't know anything of the
sort. - But you heard him. - No.
What I heard is that I'm for the chop
and they won't wait forever
to make it come true.
- Mr Dawes...
- Mr Molesley.
.. might I have a word?
There's no point in
shouting at me, Mr Skinner.
I want what you want: a
magazine people like to read.
I don't understand why you're so angry.
I'm simply making suggestions.
Well, I'm sorry you feel that way.
I will be up tomorrow, so
we can talk about it then
but, please, try and keep
calm until I get there.
Goodbye.
We should finish up. The children
will be here in a minute.
- Who was it?
- Mr Skinner in his usual form.
He hates my ideas for the editorial,
he hates my suggestions for interviews
and he hates the new
photographs we've commissioned.
Sounds as if he hates running a magazine.
He hates me. Let's leave it at that.
I'll have to go up to London, which
is a nuisance, but there you are.
How did the meeting go?
Dr Clarkson wants to win your
mother over to Granny's team.
- And will he?
- I don't believe so.
I suppose he likes being his
own boss and who can blame him?
Is that fair? It's always been a huge
plus that we have our own hospital
- and he wants to retain it.
- So whose side are you on?
I wish I didn't have to decide.
- Ah!
- Hello, my darling.
How was your day?
I never asked what that man
was here for this morning.
Malton is holding a late
fat stock show this year.
- That sounds rather small beer. Is
it worth the bother? - I think so.
Two of the pigs are
proven winners after all.
- I'm going to look at them tomorrow.
- Can we come? - I don't see why not.
I'll tell Nanny.
You want to take them to the Drewes' farm?
You can come with us if you like.
But is it a good idea? Is it safe?
Don't be such a ninny. I've
said you can come if you want.
It'll be nice for them to see Marigold.
But I have to be in London now.
I'll go.
- I'm sure it'll be fine.
- How exciting!
We'll all look at the
pigs, then we'll come home.
- Are you on your own?
- Looks like it.
Cos I've got something for you.
Oh, yes? What's that, then?
You know I went into the village earlier?
- I looked in at the school,
while I was there. - Go on...
I spoke to the headmaster
about your examination.
Well, about examinations
in general, really.
Anyway...
He suggested, before we fix a date,
you might like a go at some old
papers from the last few years.
You mean real exams that people sat?
- That was kind of you.
- Oh, don't thank me.
He took me through them. In fact,
it was really rather interesting.
I just wish Mr Mason was settled.
If you passed your exams, you'd
be in a better place to help him.
Maybe, but first, I've
got to make them listen.
Her Ladyship was there and she
tried to calm the new owner down,
- so she must be sympathetic.
- Daisy, we're servants.
I have to do something.
Is anything the matter?
No.
I mean, you're free.
Bates is free, the threat's gone away.
I'd expect you to be wreathed in smiles
but, instead, you seem rather cast down.
Life's never simple is it, milady?
You don't have to tell
me, if you don't want to.
It's almost funny really, given the
service I once performed for you.
You know Mr Bates and I have
always wanted children...?
And you'll have some now, I'm sure.
No, I won't.
It seems I can't.
Anna, no woman living
has been put through more of
an emotional wringer than you.
It doesn't surprise me in the least
that you haven't got pregnant before now.
That's the point, I can get
pregnant, I just can't keep it.
And how many times has this happened?
Two, maybe three.
Well, I still say your life has been
so filled with stress and worry...
It's all right, milady.
I'm used to the idea.
Some women can't have
children and I'm one of them.
Now, if that will be all...
Yes, thank you.
Hello.
- Do you post your own letters?
- Ha!
It was vital it went off today and
I'm never very good at delegating.
As a matter of fact, I'm glad to see you.
I'd value your advice.
I've had a letter from the
Royal Yorkshire Hospital,
asking if I'd head the new
Board of Charitable Donors.
We'd be working alongside.
Well, that's if I stay the
almoner, once we've amalgamated.
Well, of course you would. When we combine,
we'll avoid duplicating our efforts.
The whole thing would work a lot
more efficiently than it does now.
So you don't disagree with the plan?
Well, don't you see what it could mean?
How old is our X-ray machine?
Does Clarkson really know how to use it?
What advanced surgery do we offer? None.
If a family at the Abbey has a
cut finger, they go to London,
- but what about everyone else?
- I bet you'd go to London too.
I probably would, but I shouldn't have to.
And what about people who
don't have that option?
So the battle lines are drawn
and now we must fight it out.
Well, I'm glad we're to be allies.
I must be going.
I assume old Lady Grantham
is still bitterly opposed?
Of course, so there'll be wigs
on the green before we're done.
So be it. Wigs on the green it is.
Poor Daisy's in a terrible state
about Mr Mason losing his farm.
I don't blame her, it's a beautiful
place and he's a lovely man.
She seems to think that Her
Ladyship might want to help.
I don't see how. I mean, they like
Mr Mason, but what can they do?
The way she talks, they didn't
much take to the new owners.
But do you think you could ask?
I can tell her Daisy's worried,
but I can't do more than that.
Very well. I'd better get on.
- I shouldn't get involved.
- No.
And you don't like to get
involved in helping others, do you?
I'm trying to help you.
- Anything interesting?
- Is this interesting?
'Assistant butler, varied
duties, start at once.'
- Then there's a Ripon number.
- Oh.
- It would be nice if you didn't have
to move far away. - Nice for whom?
You won't let me be fond of you,
will you? No matter what I do.
- Did I leave a tin of oil in here?
- I put it on the mantelpiece. - Oh.
Mr Carson wants me to wind the clocks.
I've an idea the one in the tapestry
room needs extra loving care.
I used to wind the clocks.
Do you want some help?
Don't worry, Mr Barrow, I looked
after the clocks in my last place.
What's an assistant butler
when it's at home, anyway?
That's what I'd like to know.
- Well, they're big enough.
- They're good animals, milady.
They've done well and
they will again at Malton.
Hey, Miss Marigold!
Does Lady Edith know you're here?
She would've come herself,
but she's in London.
- So you're happy to enter them
for the show? - Very happy.
- Where's Mrs Drewe? - She's gone
into town, but she'll be back soon.
- We should probably get home.
- Well, there's no great rush.
- Won't Mrs Drewe want to see
Marigold? - Well -- - Yes, I would.
It's kind of you, milady.
I'd love to look at her.
Hello.
- Do you remember me? - Of course she
remembers you, don't you, darling?
It's been so nice, but I think we ought
to get them back for their luncheon.
Back to the big house for luncheon.
Let her go, Margie.
We mustn't hold them up.
That's it, my love, you come
with me, back to your auntie.
Good, well, I'll send a note
to Mr Finch in the afternoon.
Thank you, Mr Drewe.
(I hope that's the last
time anyone calls me Auntie.)
Right, back to work.
Mr Carson?
I wonder if I could have some time
off, this afternoon, for an interview?
Interview? What, for a job?
Yes, it's quite local --
Rothley Manor near Ripon.
I telephoned and they
said to look in today.
You don't let the grass grow, I must say.
- So I can go?
- Be my guest.
Thank you, Mr Carson.
Good luck.
If I was lucky, I wouldn't be leaving.
- Did the children like the pigs?
- They loved them.
Drewe was as proud as
punch showing them off.
- Was Mrs Drewe there?
- She came just before we left
and she enjoyed seeing
Marigold, didn't she, Mama?
- She was quite overcome.
- Yes, I think she was very pleased.
Is that luncheon?
Carson, when Papa offered to
decorate the servants' hall,
he wasn't really thinking.
If you'd like your reception to be
here, we can hold it in the hall,
or whichever room you choose.
That's very kind of you, My Lady.
Not a bit, we'd be
delighted, wouldn't we, Papa?
But you must feel free to refuse.
Oh, there's not much chance of that.
- Speak to Mrs Hughes, she may
feel differently. - Why should she?
She just may, that's all, it's
her wedding. Shall we go in?
Of course, I'd have been very happy
in the servants' hall, My Lord...
Don't worry, Carson, there's
no point even pretending
that we can argue with
Lady Mary, either of us.
This isn't right.
- Give me a moment, I'll be fine. - No.
I mean, it's not right
for you to cry alone.
You're married and that means you
never have to cry alone again.
I told Lady Mary last night.
She was kind, of course, but
it just brought it all back.
Have you ever thought about adoption?
Yes, but... I don't believe
it would work for you.
You're tribal, Mr Bates,
and the tribe doesn't
have a lot of members.
You want your own child.
No substitute will do.
But what do YOU want?
See. You gave yourself
away by not denying it.
We must learn to be content as we are...
.. which is easy for me.
But it's my fault, not yours, that
I can't give you what you need.
To me, we are one person and
that person can't have children.
I love you.
Of course I understand you
may have read many magazines
whilst having your hair done
or waiting for the dentist,
but that does not mean you're an
expert in how to produce them!
You know, there is no need
to shout, I am not deaf.
Oh, really? Are you sure?
Because you seem to have such
difficulty in hearing what I am saying.
- It's drier than they said it
would be in the newspapers. - Yes.
It's brightening up, isn't it?
- Let's go. - We'll have lunch
and then you can come back.
There's no point.
- What a terrible man.
- He didn't sound very conciliatory.
The truth is, I've come up to
London to have my nose bitten off
and that's not all.
Mama telephoned. Mary took
Marigold to the Drewes' farm today.
- I knew she was planning it.
- Well, why didn't you stop her?
Well, how? George was
aching to see the pigs
and what possible reason could
I give for stopping Marigold?
Well, you could've said
it would upset Mrs Drewe.
Wouldn't Mary have wondered why
I was making such a thing of it?
- You're going to have to tell her one day.
- I don't see why.
- How's Granny?
- Embarking on a civil war.
They want to change the way
they run the local hospital.
Change? Mama won't like that.
She's in one camp with Dr
Clarkson, who isn't a fan either,
- and Isobel's in the other.
- And your parents?
Mama agrees with Isobel. Papa
doesn't want to take sides.
Well, if I know Granny, he'll have to.
So you're under butler at Downton Abbey.
Yes, I've been there for a long time.
I first arrived as a junior
footman about 15 years ago.
- Another world.
- So it seems.
Of course, I was away at the
war in the middle of that.
- Why are you leaving now?
- It seems like the right time for a move.
Does it? Does it, indeed?
Tell me, Mr Moore, what exactly
is an assistant butler?
I'm not familiar with the term.
No, well, we made it up.
Ah, so the duties of an assistant butler
are not the same as an under butler.
I think you have to climb down
from that high horse, Mr Barrow.
This is 1925.
We'd need you to combine the duties of a
footman -- when needed -- and a chauffeur.
- There's no chauffeur?
- Well, they drive themselves most of the time
but, should they need a chauffeur for
evening parties and the like, that'd be you.
I see. Well, I can drive, just about.
- Is that all?
- Do you know how to valet?
Goodness, this is a job
for a one-man band.
You're a delicate-looking
fella, aren't you?
I wouldn't say that.
- Are you married?
- No.
Why would that be? Did the
right girl never come along?
I think you know that not many
footmen or butlers are married.
Well, they didn't used to be. But I am.
All right, Mr Barrow, I've got
enough. We'll let you know.
- How did the visit go? - Well, George
wants to be a pig farmer when he grows up.
- And Mr Drewe's well?
- He's so proud of his animals.
Was Mrs Drewe there?
You're full of questions.
To be honest, she was quite
upset at seeing Marigold again.
I thought it would be a nice gesture
but, perhaps, I was being insensitive.
When a woman loves a child,
it must stay with her.
I suppose so.
That reminds me...
You know what you told me, last night?
Yes.
I want you to let me help.
That's so nice, milady, thank you,
but there's nothing to be done --
That's not true. Well,
that's not necessarily true.
I think you've forgotten that,
when I was first married,
- I couldn't get pregnant, either --
- Yes, but you see, I --
Listen. So I went to a
Dr Ryder in Harley Street.
He found I needed a tiny operation,
I had it and George is the result.
- I don't think there's any point --
- There's no point in thinking, you don't know.
I'm going to take you up to London, we'll
meet Dr Ryder and listen to what he has to say.
- Then we'll see.
- But what would that cost?
I couldn't accept it from you.
Don't be silly, you've
earned it fair and square,
keeping my secrets, hiding
that fearful Dutch thingamajig,
carrying poor Mr Pamuk down the
gallery in the dead of night.
We have had our moments
haven't we, milady?
We certainly have. And
this is our next moment.
I'll telephone and make an appointment.
I do appreciate it.
It won't work, but that's not the point.
Nobody in my whole life has
been kinder to me than you have.
- Except for Mr Bates.
I'm glad that's settled.
- Will you tell him?
- Not yet.
He'd hope too much. But later,
if anything comes of it.
But how? I'd be surprised if Mr Henderson was
particularly anxious to renew our acquaintance.
Couldn't Sir John Darnley
put in a good word?
I'm sure, but the new owners
won't take orders from him.
Now that it is theirs,
they'll do as they think fit.
So I'll tell Daisy not
to speak to you about it.
I don't like anyone to feel they
can't approach me if they want to,
but I'm not convinced I can help.
- Whom can't you help?
- Mr Mason.
- I don't think I can.
- No.
What were you not saying about
your visit to the Drewes'?
Only that Mrs Drewe has
definitely not got over Marigold.
- No? - No. She looked as if
she wanted to swallow her whole.
Well, how clever was it to take the
child there in the first place?
Mary made the plan. There
was no way to cancel it.
I wish Edith would just tell her.
Oh, she thinks Mary would use it
as a weapon and she may be right.
If only the Drewes would move
away and find a tenancy elsewhere.
Why would they? They've been at
Yew Tree for more than a century.
That woman will not forget Marigold
while the girl is under her nose.
I don't mind talking to Drewe,
but I doubt it will do much good.
- Did the interview go well?
- Not very.
Never mind. Something will turn up.
But not this one.
They wanted me to be a chauffeur,
a footman and a valet combined.
For all I know, I'd have to cook and
do the garden into the bargain (!)
I suppose none of that was
reflected in the money.
Was it heck as like? They pay for
one servant and they want a whole
bleeding household thrown in.
- I don't understand why you bother with him.
- I know you don't.
- So I can't speak to Her Ladyship?
- She didn't say that,
she just said she didn't
think she could help.
I'd like to hear it from her lips, or I'll feel
I've done nothing, except make things worse.
- Well, then, ask her.
- But don't be angry with her.
It's not Her Ladyship's fault.
Maybe not, but it's the system's fault.
That's what makes me angry -- the
system -- and she's part of it.
I do not understand why any
form of compromise is beyond him.
You wanted a strong editor.
But I didn't want to find myself
in a bull ring with Attila the Hun.
Thank you, William.
- Oh... Mary's coming tomorrow.
- What does she want?
She has an appointment in Harley
Street and she needs some clothes.
I ought to do some
shopping while I'm here.
I haven't had anything new in ages.
- Why not go shopping together?
- With Mary? Not likely.
- That was a delicious dinner.
- Oh, I have a new cook.
She won't stay -- the good ones never do,
but we shall eat well until she goes.
What have you decided
to do about your flat?
I think I'm going to keep it empty
and see if I get any use out of it.
- Why aren't you there now?
- I should be.
I suppose the truth is
I've never lived alone
and I'm not convinced
I'll be much good at it.
Beware of being too good at it.
That's the danger of living alone
-- it can be very hard to give up.
It's not that I'm ungrateful, I am
grateful, I think it's very kind.
But you don't want to accept?
This is a beautiful house
and whether we're in the great hall
or the drawing room, or wherever,
it would all be very splendid.
- So what's the problem?
- It's not us.
It's not who we are.
It may be where we work,
but it is not who we are.
While being in the school house would be?
It doesn't have to be the school
house, if you don't like it.
But, yes, if we take a neutral place
and decorate it the way we want
and put in the flowers we
like, it would be about us
in a way the great hall of
Downton Abbey never can be.
And I have to tell His Lordship.
I will, if you don't want to.
No, no, I'll do it. It should be me.
Do you know when you'll be back?
Tomorrow, or the next day, I expect.
What does she have planned?
Oh, you know, some shopping,
one or two appointments.
Well, try and put your feet up.
Yes, I'll be putting my feet up.
I think a bit of a break will do you good
and give my regards to Mr Mead.
You're right, it may do me good.
It won't do any harm, anyway.
To what do we owe this honour?
I must look in at the church
and I'm seeing Dr Clarkson and
Mama at the hospital later on.
I've mentioned it to Isobel,
so I hope she's there too.
- Is that wise?
- I think so.
At least she's an ally I can rely
on, even if I can't rely on you.
- I didn't tell you about the m - What
time's your train? - Half-past nine.
- Bags of time. - Carson, have
you broken the news to Mrs Hughes?
- What news is this?
- Where they're having the wedding reception.
- I hope she's pleased. - To be honest,
My Lady, she's a little hesitant.
She's not quite convinced
that it would be appropriate.
- Why not? - She feels we would be
making a claim to which we have no right.
Carson, you've worked in this house
man and boy for half a century.
If you've no right to be married
from here, then who does?
- Mrs Hughes sees it differently.
- You leave Mrs Hughes to me.
Don't worry, Carson, your reception will be
in the great hall if it's the last thing I do.
How reassuring, My Lady.
How very reassuring.
We wanted you to see the
ward now it's been repainted.
- It's much brighter, isn't it?
- Very nice.
Doctor?
He's done this with me, my dear.
Now you'll be paraded past
every element of treatment:
surgical, palliative, you name it.
Oh? And what are you trying to add?
I don't want Cousin
Cora to feel outnumbered.
It isn't friendly, you know,
to stir her up into opposition.
It's not very friendly to squash
her into submission either.
Excuse me, but I don't need
to be stirred or squashed.
- The facts speak for themselves.
- Your facts or mine?
- What's the difference?
- Mine are the true facts.
Shall we continue this in my office?
I wish we could persuade you to
help us stem the tide of change.
I'm just not convinced it's the
right way forward, to go backward.
I do not understand you, my dear.
- Are you saying Dr Clarkson is
a bad doctor? - Certainly not.
And the other doctors that use our
hospital -- are they no good either?
I'm sure everyone does their very best,
but there are new methods now,
new treatments, new machines.
Great advances have
been made since the war.
- Can't we share in them?
- Hear, hear.
Of course. I intend that we should.
- We haven't got the money.
- I see I'm not needed to lend you strength.
You're fully in command of the argument.
Have you no pride in what we
have achieved with our hospital?
I don't think pride comes into it.
Well, I warn you, Dr Clarkson and
I will fight to the last ditch.
I just want what's best for the village.
Well, at least we have that in common.
I must go. Mama, Isobel...
I'll come with you.
We must give them time to
gnash their teeth alone.
I can't deny it, Lady Grantham
would've made a powerful ally.
I hope you're not implying that
she would be more powerful than I.
- Oh, no, indeed.
- Mm.
- Are you ordering me to leave?
- Of course not,
but the fact remains, this
is a difficult situation.
Why did they bring her here?
Why didn't Lady Edith stop it?
She couldn't, she was away.
Where's Mrs Drewe now?
She's collecting the children from school.
We're all right.
I wish we were all right.
Nobody wishes it more than I do,
but Her Ladyship worries that Mrs Drewe
simply cannot stand being so near the child.
Don't push us out, milord.
We've been here since before Waterloo.
I'm not pushing anyone anywhere.
I want Lady Edith to be happy and
I want Miss Marigold to be happy
and as a matter of fact, I would
like your wife to be happy too.
I can manage her, I promise.
- Very well, if you're sure you can.
- I am sure.
Then we'll leave it at that.
Did you manage to raise the subject?
His Lordship brought it up.
How did he take it when you refused?
Oh. You didn't refuse, did you?
It was difficult.
Lady Mary feels... that it's only right
that my marriage is
celebrated in the house.
And heaven forfend we lowly folk should do
anything to contradict the blessed Lady Mary!
- That's not like you.
- It is very like me.
I want my own wedding to
be done in my own way.
- Is that so outlandish?
- It's my wedding too.
But I am the bride, we'll be doing
it your way for the next 30 years,
I know that well enough,
but the wedding day is mine.
- What is it? - Your Ladyship,
might Daisy have a word with you?
- Now?
- She's just outside.
Very well.
Thank you for seeing me, milady.
I'm happy to, Daisy, but I
must tell you right off,
- there's nothing more I can do.
- I just can't bear it
for our William's dad to be thrown out
of his farm when it's all my fault.
To start with, I don't
think it is your fault.
Mr Henderson was angry, but he
wouldn't change his plans for that
and the truth is, they are taking
a lot of the estate in hand.
But Mr Mason's not young and
it needs someone that knows him.
I'm sure he has a fine reputation
and Sir John Darnley will help.
He's got all the dead stock,
with everything in top shape.
Any estate would be lucky to have him.
And he'd be happy to start
anew? It's a big undertaking.
Why?
Have you thought of something?
- You've had an idea, haven't you?
- Probably not.
Well, maybe.
I'll let you know if anything comes of it.
Thank you, Your Ladyship.
It's no mystery, Mrs Bates, you
suffer from cervical incompetence.
To put it plainly, the
neck of the womb is weak
and as the foetus reaches
three or four months,
it becomes too heavy to be supported.
- So it's not unusual?
- It's bad luck, but not unusual.
- And you can treat it?
- Certainly.
The procedure is called cervical cerclage.
- It's been in use for more
than 20 years. - Go on.
I would insert a stitch, quite a
large one, in the neck of the womb.
- Is it painful?
- It's quite quick.
- But it works? - I'm afraid I
can't make a blanket promise.
It works in many cases.
- And when would you do it?
- At about 12 weeks.
I'd normally come to your
house and perform it there,
then you can rest afterwards
without the nuisance of travel.
- I wouldn't go to hospital?
- Oh, no, it's not worth it.
Well, you've given me a lot
to think about, Doctor.
Thank you.
- When do you return north?
- In the morning.
Then I leave it to you to get in touch if and
when you next become pregnant, Mrs Bates.
I'm afraid Drewe won't leave.
I can't pretend I really blame him.
But I don't believe the
problem will go away either.
Edith telephoned before I came up.
It seems her editor continues
to be a nightmare too.
Did she say when she's coming back?
She and Mary are catching the
same train tomorrow, 11 o'clock.
Travelling together? Heavens to Betsy!
But I'm glad Mary's coming straight back.
As it is, she'll only have two days
to get the pigs ready for the show.
Don't worry, it's only a fat stock
show and they're pretty low-key.
Two days is more than enough.
Still, I'm glad she's doing it.
These things remind the farming community
that we're all on the same side.
I wish we could remind your mother
that we're on the same side.
I don't think the rule applies to Mama.
- She's a law unto herself.
- And don't we know it?
Is there more sugar?
Here, pop one in there for us.
Right, as you're all aware, this
is the day of the Malton show.
There'll be no upstairs luncheon
and you're all free to
visit the show if you wish.
The wagonette will leave
from the stable yard at ten.
- Is there a lunch we're serving at?
- No, they're guests of Lord Mexborough.
I don't think I'll bother. It's
only a muddy, little affair.
Oh, no, you should come.
I think it'll be fun.
You're full of the joys of spring.
- Am I?
- I was right about London.
- You've been very bouncy since you
got back. It did you good. - It did.
Now let me get on. I'll see you
down here, just before ten.
- How long can we stay there?
- Good question.
I must have a staff to serve
tea in case they want it.
- I could do that.
- I don't think so.
Andrew, Mr Molesley, make sure
you're here by a quarter-past four.
Then when do you need me, Mr Carson?
When indeed?
- How are they doing today?
- Fine fettle, milady.
- Moo! - Look at that cow. - Moo!
- You made it, then?
- Did you think I wouldn't?
Oh, they're all here, then.
You knew they would be. Come on.
Never mind. Do you want to see
Lady Mary showing off her pigs?
In a minute.
Here, let me show you.
Don't worry, Mr Barrow. It's not my game.
I'd better go. I don't
want to miss those pigs.
You're not a quick learner, are you?
I don't know what you mean, Mrs Patmore.
I'm only thinking of you. Just
be sensible, for heaven's sake.
Does it ever occur to you that,
just this once, you might be wrong?
Well done, milady. You look
as if you're born to it.
Not a compliment to everyone's
taste, Mr Finch, but it is to mine.
It's funny to see Lady Mary
in there with the pigs.
I think it does her proud.
I agree. People might think she's
a pretend farmer, but she's not.
- I hope things are beginning to settle
down for you, Mr Mason. - Settle down?
- They're beginning to break
apart, more like. - Don't say it.
Only poor Daisy can hardly work,
she's been so worried about you.
Nae, Daisy, you can't let
worry put you off your work.
Brava. You look very convincing.
- My god-daughter, the pig breeder.
- So good of you to come.
One of my tenants has an
entry, I came to support him,
so you're a bonus, my dear.
Mama says you're on her side
for the battle of the hospitals.
Well, I believe in the changes, yes.
Naturally, Granny blames Isobel for
drawing you over to the dark side.
Oh, no, no, no. I was
on the dark side anyway.
Oh! I was rather hoping it might
be the first signs of a thaw.
How I wish that were true but, I'm
afraid, her mind remains made up.
A woman can always change her mind,
it's what we're known for. Ah...
- Hello, Mrs Drewe. Everyone well?
- Very well, thank you, milord,
but I've left the
children with my neighbour.
- Tim thought I should have a day off
to enjoy myself. - Quite right too.
Nice to see you.
What else would you like to do?
If you're asking, could we get this
business sorted for good and all?
I don't mean to sound stubborn,
but surely it is sorted.
It means a lot to Lady Mary and the
family that we're married in the house
- and I can't see why we shouldn't be.
- You can't?
No, I can't.
If we had family nearby, or a
place that meant something special,
it'd be different, but we don't
and Downton Abbey means much
more to me than the school.
I'm sorry, but it does.
My lords, ladies and gentlemen,
- it is time for the announcement
for Best In Show. - Ah!
- First prize goes to Golden
Empress of Downton Abbey. - Oh!
Earned by the Earl of
Grantham and Lady Mary Crawley.
- Very good.
- Pig man -- Mr Timothy Drewe.
Well done, My Lord.
Yes, well done, us.
Where's Miss Marigold, milady?
She was... Who's got Marigold?
- She was here just...
- No, she's gone.
- I gather we've won.
- Yes, but Miss Marigold's missing.
- What? - Oh, my god. - Don't worry,
she's just wandered off. She's fine.
She'll be perfectly fine, you'll see.
- What is it?
- Marigold's gone.
I was talking to your wife and
Marigold was just in front of us.
How could I possibly
have lost sight of her?
Stay with your mother.
Everyone spread out. Carson!
I'm coming with you.
Barrow, come with me.
- What is it, milady?
- We're missing Miss Marigold.
- Don't say that word.
- Don't be silly.
She's missing now and
soon she'll be found.
- Any luck?
- I'm afraid not, milord.
Barrow...
- Have you got a car here, milady?
- What? No, I came with my parents.
- Why?
- I know where we'll find her.
- Where? - I've just realised Margie's
gone too and she's taken the truck.
- You mean she... - I'm afraid so,
milady, but don't worry, she won't hurt her.
Whatever she does, she won't hurt
her. Calm them down and let's go.
It's all right, we had a message.
Mrs Drewe found her and has taken
her home to be out of harm's way.
- Could you take me there now
to collect her? - Of course.
I'll get the car.
- What's going on?
- Panic over, milady.
Miss Marigold's at Yew
Tree Farm with Mrs Drewe.
- They've just gone to fetch her now.
- At the farm with Mrs Drewe? Why?
She took her there for safety.
It was good of her, really.
And how will we get back?
Please, let me go in alone.
- I'll come.
- No, I don't wanna frighten her.
Let him, he knows what he's doing.
She was bored.
They were paying her no
attention, none at all.
So you brought her here.
Where else would I bring her?
This is her home...
.. and no-one was looking
after her, not one of 'em.
Give her to me now.
You're not angry are you, Tim?
Surely, you can't be angry that
I only want to hold her close
and love her as much as I can.
No, my darling.
I'm not angry at all.
But give her to me...
.. please.
There we are, safe and sound.
Hello, darling.
Let's get you back in
the car and off home.
I'll start looking for another
tenancy in the morning.
I am sorry, Drewe.
I want to help as much as I can.
Please, just tell me if there's
anything you need from me.
- That's very kind of you, milord.
- It's not kind.
It's a poor return for what you
and Mrs Drewe have done for us.
- I know how much Lady Edith...
- There you are.
- .. know how much all of us owe to
you and your wife. - Don't feel badly.
We made a plan, Lady Edith and
I, but we forgot about emotion...
.. and emotion's what can
trip you up every time.
God bless you, Drewe.
God bless you and your family.
The same to you, milord.
The very same to you.
He's agreed.
It seems very unfair, but I've
thought and thought about it
and I don't see what else we can do.
I think it's for the best.
I know it's for the best.
- Did you drink at luncheon?
- No, I did not.
One wrong move and snap,
you're out on your ear.
You think I'm a bully.
I think you're a snob.
- I don't suppose you'd like a drink with me?
- All right. Why not?
I'm surprised at you, Mrs Hughes. This is
not the behaviour I would look for from you.
Mr Spratt seems very
preoccupied at the moment.
- This is the tonic Mr Mason needs.
- But it's not definite yet.
- We've come to dress the bride.
- There's a sentence I never thought I'd hear.